ICICI LBRD, a general insurance
company, declared its quarter 4 results on April 15.  The
company's revenue
growth has been strong, but profit growth is
not as impressive.  So let's
analyze the result in simple language.
In this video we will cover these topics.
Such as top line growth, bottom
line growth, revenue growth overview with
previous years, PE valuation, balance
sheet overview and also see how many
dividends were announced.
If we talk about the quick summary of the results, the
company's revenue grew by about 13%.
But net profit growth was only 7.3%.
This growth has happened on year on year basis.  At
the same time, the company's operating profit
margin declined to only 10%.  Now let's
talk about the company's revenue.
In the insurance business, revenue means
premium growth.  The company's
revenue grew by 13% to Rs 6825 crore.
13% growth means the company is
expanding its business and the
demand in this sector is also stable.
Now let's come to net profit.  Here's something
interesting.  Revenue grew by 13%
but profit grew by only 7.3%,
meaning the company is earning more but is
not able to convert that much into profit efficiently.
This means that the company
's operating profit margins are under pressure and have
declined to only 10% in this quarter.
If we compare the revenue with last year,
we see that the company's revenue has
grown continuously.  The company's total revenue was expected to be Rs
2057 crore in 2024, which grew to Rs
23961 crore in 2025 and now it will grow to Rs
26,994
crore in 2026.  Now talking about the
PE ratio of the company, the PE has now reached around 25,
which is much below its mean PE which is
40 and from this chart we
can see that the valuation of the company is
continuously adjusting.  There is EPS
growth, but the PE ratio
is continuously normalizing due to which
this stock is in a phase of consolidation for quite some time.
Now talking about the balance sheet of the company, the
company has zero debt and the company has
cash reserves of around ₹987 crore and the
balance sheet of the company is strong.  Now
talking about dividend, the company's board has
approved a dividend of ₹7.
What is your view on ICICI LBA, please do tell us in the comments.